Inventory of the Peace subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- INCREMENTAL MATERIAL, 1910-2005; 14-17 (Box 14-17:)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, Research and Publication Projects, circa 1946 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Christen für die Abrüstung, 1981 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Christen gegen die Atomrüstung, 1981 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Church and Peace, 1978 (Folder 15: 8)
  - Conference on the Limitation of Armament, Washington, D.C., 1921-1922 (Folder 15: 9-10)
  - De Schnüs, 1981 (Folder 15: 11)
  - Deutsche Gesellschaft für Friedens, 1981 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Dokumentationsstätte zu Kriegsgeschehen und über Friedensarbeit, 1980-1982 (Folder 15: 13)
  - EIRENE - Internationaler Christlicher Friedensdienst e.V., 1981 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Frieden schaffen ohne Waffen, 1981 (Folder 15: 15)
  - Friedensmanifestation, 1979 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Gulf War, 1991 (Folder 16: 2-4)
  - Human Rights and Rule of Law: What?s the Relationship? by Randall Peerenboom, 2005 (Folder 16: 5)
  - Integration study reports, 1921-1954 (Folder 16: 6)
  - International peace studies, 1982-1984 (Folder 16: 7)
  - Internationalen Versöhnungsbundes, 1981 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Krefelder Appeall, 1981 (Folder 16: 9)
  - League of Nations, minutes of meetings, printed matter, 1931-1947 (Folder 16: 10-11)
  - League to Enforce Peace, 1916 (Folder 16: 12)
  - Maxwell Memorial Foundation, 1950-1951 (Folder 16: 13)
  - Mit freundlichen Grüï¿½en, circa 1982 (Folder 17: 1)
  - Mut für eine bessere Zukunft, 1982 (Folder 17: 2)
  - "Notes on the Peace Flag," by Bruno Guissani, 2004 (Folder 17: 3)
    Includes the flag
  - Paris Peace Conference, 1919 (Folder 17: 4)
    See also boxes 18-22
  - Pax Christi, circa 1980 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Preventing nuclear war, 1982-1984 (Folder 17: 6)
  - Security and arms control, 1983-1992 (Folder 17: 7)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD), 1981-1982 (Folder 17: 8)
  - Sozialistischer Hochschulbund (SHB), 1981 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Terre des Hommes, 1979-1982 (Folder 17: 10)
  - United Nations idea in Berkeley, California, 1908-1960 (Folder 17: 11)
  - Verein für Friedenspädagogik Tübingen, 1981 (Folder 17: 12)
  - World Gathering of Women for Disarmament, 1962 (Folder 17: 13)
  - World Peace Foundation, second conference on distribution of documentary materials, 1947 (Folder 17: 14-15)
  - World Wide Peacekeeping Operations, 1994, Central Intelligence Agency, map (Folder 17: 16)
- SCRAPBOOKS, 1919; 18-22 (Box 18-22: 16)
  Includes five oversized scrapbooks of French press clippings about the Paris Peace Conference
  - Paris Peace Conference, French press clippings, March-August, 1919 (Folder 18-22)
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1981 (Box Cassette cabinet)
  Contains four compact sound cassettes
  - Gegen die Atomare Bedrohung Gemeinsam Vorgehen, Tondokumentation 1-4, Bonn, 10.10.81, 4 compact sound cassettes
    Part 1: Bots (1.43) Harry Belafonte (2.52) Begrüßung und Verlesen des Aufrufes (7.06) Heinrich Albertz (14.26) Alfred Mechtersheimer (Teil 1, 2.19)
    Part 2: Alfred Mechtersheimer (Teil 2, 3.55) Liedvortrag Gabi Scherle-Reike (1.96) Greetje Witte-Rang (7.41) Randal Forsberg (11.05)
    Part 3: Perry Friedmann (4.46) Coretta Scott-King (9.35) Martin Niemöller (7.85) Nino Pasti (1.38)
    Part 4: Thomas Heubeck (6.39) Georg Benz (14.23) Gewerkschaftschor (1.46)
    Part 5: Erhard Eppler (14.57) William Borm (11.28) Robert Jungk (Teil 1, 2.12)
    Part 6: Robert Jungk (Teil 2, 5.08) Zwischenrede (0.45) Helmut Ridder (11.30) Angi Domdey (1.15) Petra Kelly (8.33)
    Part 7: Gerd Bastian (6.30) Uta Ranke-Heinemann (12.08) Das ,,Nein von Bonn'' (4.15) Zwischenrede (2.07)
    Part 8: Schlußwort der Veranstalter (4.33) Heinrich Böll (16.38) We shall overcome (4.04)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: xx761_a_0013294